const e="We could not find what you asked for, but got you this",a="crk",t=200,i=120,o=[{id:66,question:"Bring your necks under the yoke of the king of Babylon and serve him and his people and live” who gave this advice? ",option:{a:"Jeremiah ",b:"Isaiah ",c:"Ezekiel ",d:"Amos"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2008"},{id:898,question:"Who among the following was to ensure the safety of King Saul in the wilderness of Ziph? ",option:{a:"Joab           ",b:"Jonathan          ",c:"Abner           ",d:"  Abimelech"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2013"},{id:682,question:"According to Paul, ‘As sin reigned in death, grace also might reign through righteousness to",option:{a:"faith in God’.",b:"the knowledge of God’.",c:"eternal life",d:"the glory of the father’."},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2011"},{id:1077,question:"The charge of drunkenness was levelled against the apostles on Pentecost day because",option:{a:"they were drunk before nine o’clock ",b:"they spoke in other tongues",c:"a power descended on them ",d:"they made an unintelligible noise"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2015"},{id:1045,question:"Jacob’s special robe for Joseph portrayed him as a",option:{a:"Prince    ",b:"heir     ",c:"prophet     ",d:"Pries"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2015"},{id:119,question:"“It is not the sound of shouting for victory, or the sound of the cry of defeat, but the sound of singing that I hear” When was this statement made? ",option:{a:"at the consecration of the Israelites ",b:"at the crossing of the Red Sea ",c:"during the fall of Jericho ",d:"in a strange worship of a god"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:406,question:"‘...why then have you not kept watch over your lord the king?...” The question above by David was addressed to",option:{a:"Amasa",b:"Joab",c:"Abishai",d:"Abner."},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2013"},{id:802,question:"Solomon told Hiram, King of Tyre, that he had decided to ",option:{a:"the Lord had given him peace and all good things. ",b:"his father, David, never intended to build one",c:"C he wanted to force Hiram to come to his ai",d:"C he wanted to force Hiram to come to his ai"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2010"},{id:832,question:"In Corinthians, Paul cited all the following resurrection appearances of Jesus except ",option:{a:"Cephas.    ",b:"The Twelve.   ",c:"Mary Magdalene   ",d:"James"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2010"},{id:284,question:"After Prophet Ezekiel had eaten what he was offered, he was sent to speak to",option:{a:"a people of hard language",b:"the house of Israel",c:"the house of Judah",d:"a people of foreign language"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2009"},{id:408,question:"Saul relied on a medium because God did not answer him through",option:{a:"dreams, visions and prophets",b:"inspiration, tambourines and prophets",c:"dreams, urim and prophets",d:"lyre, urim and prophets."},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2013"},{id:1085,question:"James advised against looking down on the poor because they are",option:{a:"the rightful heirs of the kingdom ",b:"those who spent time on the Lord",c:"for peace and self sacrifice",d:"those who contribute little but do a lot"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2015"},{id:349,question:"Which of the following was not part of the honour done to Joseph when Pharaoh made him a ruler in Egypt?",option:{a:"Joseph was made to address the people",b:"The land of Goshen was given to Joseph",c:"Joseph was dressed in garments of fine linen",d:"A gold chain was put around Joseph’s neck."},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2008"},{id:56,question:"He shall save his people from their sins. Who is being referred to here? ",option:{a:"John the Baptist ",b:"Elijah ",c:"Elisha ",d:"Jesus"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2008"},{id:370,question:"Which of the following miracles shows Jesus’ power over nature?",option:{a:"Walking on the sea",b:"Healing of the leper",c:"Healing of the woman with issue of blood",d:"Raising of Lazarus from the dead"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2008"},{id:465,question:"The king planned to set Daniel over the whole kingdom because,",option:{a:"he was the most educated of all.",b:"an excellent spirit was in him.",c:"he wanted to favour a foreigner.",d:"Daniel brought information to the king."},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2009"},{id:467,question:"The first batch of Jewish exiles to rebuild the temple was under the leadership of",option:{a:"Joshua.",b:"Hanani.",c:"Sheshbazzar.",d:"Zerubabel."},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2009"},{id:240,question:"Paul taught the Colossians that the relationship between wives and their husbands should be as",option:{a:"is fitting in the Lord",b:"the culture demands",c:"is written in the law",d:"the husband commands"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2005"},{id:133,question:"Who according to James blaspheme the honourable name by which Christians are called",option:{a:"Non believers",b:"Pagan rulers",c:"Antichrists",d:"Rich people"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2011"},{id:617,question:"‘... But let justice roll down like waters, and righteousness like an overflowing stream.’ Amos’ statement above suggests that the society was terribly",option:{a:"vindictive",b:"abusive",c:"oppressive",d:"destructive"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:989,question:"Which of Paul’s epistle was written to an individual?",option:{a:"Romans ",b:"Corinthians   ",c:"Colossians    ",d:"Philemon"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2011"},{id:23,question:"What is meant by the Christian doctrine that God is Trinity? ",option:{a:"the idea started in Trinidad and Tobago ",b:"God is three persons in one ",c:"God is omnipotent ",d:"God is the Holy Spirit"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2006"},{id:582,question:"The man who delivered judgment of the Jerusalem Council on the admission of Gentiles into the Church was",option:{a:"Peter.",b:"Paul.",c:"Barnabas.",d:"James."},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2010"},{id:670,question:"Peter called for the construction of three booths for Jesus, Moses and Elijah, respectively during",option:{a:"the transfiguration.",b:"the Ascension.",c:"Jesus’ arrest.",d:"the Passover feast."},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2011"},{id:450,question:"The episode of David and Bathsheba, Uriah’s wife was in 	violation of God’s",option:{a:"sixth commandment.",b:"seventh commandment,",c:"eight commandment.",d:"ninth commandment."},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2009"},{id:730,question:"St Paul, in 'Law and Grace', although man was condemned, he has been redeemed through the _____",option:{a:"Compliance to the laws of the God",b:"Righteousness of his deeds",c:"Grace of God",d:"Faith in Christ Jesus"},section:"",image:"",answer:" c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2019"},{id:962,question:"All the following took place at the transfiguration of Jesus except that",option:{a:"a voice was heard from heaven.",b:"a dove came down upon Jesus",c:"the face of Jesus was changed",d:"Jesus’ clothes became dazzling white."},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2011"},{id:297,question:"God blessed and hallowed the seventh day because",option:{a:"it was the day He rested from creation",b:"it was the day He created man",c:"He wanted it to be a day of worship",d:"He saw that all He had created was good."},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2011"},{id:845,question:"God made Pharaoh to chase and bring the Israelites back to Egypt so that He would",option:{a:"show that Moses was his true servant",b:"destroy first born males of Egyptians",c:"get glory over Pharaoh and his hosts",d:"reveal his supernatural powers to the world"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2012"},{id:385,question:"In the Epistle to Galatians, Christians are children of God through",option:{a:"faith in Christ",b:"keeping of the law",c:"helping the needy",d:"baptism and confirmation"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2008"},{id:818,question:"St. John refers to Jesus’ miracles as ‘signs’ because they ",option:{a:"acceptance of Jesus as son of Go ",b:"proofs of the kingdom of Go ",c:"faith in Jesus as the means to eternal life.    ",d:"demand for more wonders"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2010"},{id:1028,question:"Paul in Romans declared “for as by one man’s disobedience many were made sinners, so by one man’s obedience many  will be made...” ",option:{a:"innocent.                 ",b:"righteous.",c:"faithful.",d:"Christians"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2011"},{id:668,question:"The presentation of Myrrh to Jesus signifies Jesus’",option:{a:"humility and servant hood.",b:"suffering and impending death.",c:"lordship on earth.",d:"kingship and messiah ship."},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2011"},{id:828,question:"Why according to Paul must Christians be subject to civil authority? ",option:{a:"To receive God’s approval ",b:"To avoid God’s wrath ",c:"God has commanded it ",d:"It is an Old Testament law "},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2010"},{id:504,question:"God displayed His supremacy when Ahab was king during 	the",option:{a:"incidence of Naboth’s vineyard",b:"war with Ramoth-gilead",c:"inciting of Jehoshaphat against him",d:"contest of Mount Carmel"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2015"},{id:355,question:"When David spared the life of Saul the second time he took away his",option:{a:"bow and arrow",b:"spear and jar of water",c:"royal crown and armour",d:"spear and iron shield."},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2008"},{id:216,question:"Jesus said “Not everyone who says to me ‘Lord, Lord,’ shall enter into the kingdom of heaven, but he who",option:{a:"hears the word of God”.",b:"prays and fasts’",c:"prophesies in my name”",d:"does the will of my father”"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2005"},{id:812,question:" Before their first encounter with Jesus, Peter and Andrew  were   ",option:{a:"preachers.     ",b:"tax collectors. ",c:"fishermen.    ",d:"tent makers."},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2010"},{id:174,question:"Israel went into Assyria captivity in",option:{a:"720BC  ",b:"730 AD   ",c:"750BC",d:"722 BC"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2013"},{id:763,question:"St Paul's teaching on spiritual gifts was directed to _______",option:{a:"Corinthians",b:"Thessalonians",c:"Galatians",d:"Macedonians"},section:"",image:"",answer:" a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2019"},{id:46,question:"Which of the following prophets was described as weeping prophet? ",option:{a:"Amos ",b:"Ezekiel ",c:"Jeremiah ",d:"Zephaniah."},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2007"},{id:1060,question:"According to Ezra, the return of the Jews from exile was prophesied by",option:{a:"Ezekiel      ",b:"  Amos    ",c:"Isaiah         ",d:"Jeremiah"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2015"},{id:303,question:"Why was God angry with Eli?",option:{a:"Eli’s sons disregarded the people’s warning",b:"Eli’s sons were wicked people.",c:"Eli’s sons dishonoured God and he treated them with levity.",d:"Eli’s sons were appointed as priests against God’s will."},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2011"},{id:638,question:"Peter in his teaching no humility, admonishes Christians to",option:{a:"safeguard their faith",b:"seek things that are above",c:"be gentle in spirit",d:"avoid life’s anxiety"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:307,question:"‘Do not destroy him; for who can stretch out his hand on the LORD’S anointed, and be guiltless?’ In the statement above, David was acknowledging God’s role in",option:{a:"Abishai’s command",b:"Saul’s leadership",c:"Samuel’s priesthood",d:"Elijah’s prophet hood."},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2011"},{id:600,question:"What was Samson’s major achievement as Israel’s leader?",option:{a:"He suppressed the Philistines",b:"He captured the city of Jericho",c:"He saved the Israelites from the Amorites",d:"He secured permanent independence for Israel"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:126,question:"The last born of Gomer for Hoshea was ………….  ",option:{a:"Jezreel",b:"Loammi ",c:"Diblaim  ",d:"Loruhamah "},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2011"},{id:485,question:"Peter urged all Christians to endure sufferings in faith conscious of the fact that",option:{a:"Jesus, himself also resisted suffering",b:"the devil could lure them from faith with suffering.",c:"only the physical body is affected.",d:"suffering is temporary and leads to eternal glory."},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2009"},{id:793,question:"  The wife of  Moses was called   ",option:{a:"Rebecca",b:"Rachel",c:"Zipporah",d:"Deborah"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2010"},{id:351,question:"God led the Israelites in the wilderness during the day in form of",option:{a:"fire",b:"light",c:"cloud",d:"rainbow."},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2008"},{id:234,question:"According to Romans, when civil authorities punish evil doers, they do so as the",option:{a:"agents of God’s wrath",b:"supervisory authority",c:"agents of the darkness of this world",d:"representatives of angelic powers"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2005"},{id:255,question:"According to Matthew, the stone on the tomb of Jesus was removed by",option:{a:"an angel",b:"a Roman soldier",c:"Mary Magdalene",d:"Peter and John."},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2009"},{id:1058,question:"Which of the following events could be attributed to Josiah? ",option:{a:"Establishing relationship with Assyria ",b:"Reconstruction of the valley of Hinnon ",c:"Revival of the feast of the Passover ",d:"Building walls around Jerusalem"},section:"      ",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2015"},{id:914,question:"Which of the following parables alludes to the existence of a mixture of good and bad people in the church? The",option:{a:"Wicked Tenants.",b:"Seed Growing Secretly.",c:"Wheat and Tares.",d:"Prodigal Son"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2013"},{id:39,question:"One of the following said: “the lion has roared who will not fear? The Lord has spoken, who can  but prophesy?” ",option:{a:"Nathan ",b:"Jeremiah ",c:"Amos ",d:"Hosea"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2007"},{id:888,question:"Partially according to James is manifested in the Church through",option:{a:"discrimination",b:"charity",c:"affection",d:"impartiality"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2012"},{id:1033,question:"According to Paul in Corinthians the gospel message could only be lifeless when Christians ",option:{a:"deny the resurrection message.    ",b:"persecute one another. ",c:"gossip among themselves. ",d:"entertain idolatrous practices"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2011"},{id:1089,question:"Peter believed that God appreciates and gives credit to servants who",option:{a:"pray without ceasing    ",b:"keep their tongues shut ",c:"fail to honour wicked masters ",d:"suffer for wrongs hot done"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2015"},{id:211,question:"Who among the prophets was referred to as a prophet of doom?",option:{a:"Isaiah",b:"Ezekiel",c:"Amos",d:"Jeremiah"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2005"},{id:535,question:"In his teaching on Spiritual gifts in Corinthians, Paul said that all gifts are inspired by",option:{a:"the same Spirit",b:"prayer",c:"the individual’s ability",d:"grace"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2015"},{id:191,question:"Who was the prophet who said “I will put my law within them, and will write it upon their heart….”?  ",option:{a:"Isaiah  ",b:"Jeremiah",c:"Hosea   ",d:"Amos"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2013"},{id:648,question:"“…who is the Lord that I should heed his voice and let Israel go”? After this statement, Pharaoh",option:{a:"engaged Israel into forced labour with task masters.",b:"ordered midwives to kill all males born to Israelites.",c:"asked Israelites to fetch their own straws to produce bricks.",d:"decreed that Israelites’ male babies be drowned in the Nile."},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2011"},{id:449,question:"Pharaoh’s horsemen and his army overtook the fleeing Hebrews encamped by the sea at",option:{a:"Migdol.",b:"Etham.",c:"Phiahiroth.",d:"Meriba."},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2009"},{id:154,question:"One of the following is not among the reasons why Jesus taught in Parables  ",option:{a:"to fulfill the prophecy in Psalm 78:2  ",b:"to create understanding  ",c:"to make people learn the unknown through the known  ",d:"to show the omniscient power of Jesus"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2012"},{id:177,question:"“Talitha cumi” means",option:{a:"Dorcas, Arise   ",b:"Little girl, I say to you, arise  ",c:"Thy will be done",d:"Jesus is coming"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2013"},{id:275,question:"Saul leant from Samuel’s spirit that the LORD would",option:{a:"give the Philistines into his hands",b:"afflict him with sickness",c:"because Isaac’s future wife",d:"pardon his iniquity"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2009"},{id:567,question:"Before their first encounter with Jesus, Peter and Andrew were",option:{a:"preachers.",b:"tax collectors.",c:"fishermen.",d:"tent makers."},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2010"},{id:635,question:"‘Unless you are circumcised according to the custom of Moses, you cannot be saved.’ The statement above by the men from Judea led to the",option:{a:"murmurs of the Hellenists",b:"convening of the Jerusalem Council",c:"persecution that scattered the disciples",d:"circumcision of the Gentiles."},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:684,question:"Which of the following is not true about spiritual gifts as taught by Paul?",option:{a:"Gifts should be used with all modesty",b:"No gift can be independent of others",c:"Gifts have nothing to do with the level of one’s faith",d:"Specific gifts perform specific functions"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2011"},{id:257,question:"“...but should write to them to abstain from the pollutions of idols and from unchastity and from what is strangled and from blood...” The statement above was made at the Council of Jerusalem by",option:{a:"Philip",b:"Simon",c:"James",d:"Peter"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2009"},{id:230,question:"Which of the following was not characteristic of the Early Church?",option:{a:"Constant change in leadership",b:"Devotion to the teachings of the apostles",c:"Breaking bread in members’ homes",d:"Communal fellowship"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2005"},{id:868,question:"The two Old Testament books that were used in the temptation stories were",option:{a:"Genesis and Proverbs",b:"Leviticus and Lamentation",c:" Numbers and Ecclesiates",d:"Deuteronomy and Psalms"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2012"},{id:618,question:"Isaiah emphasized holiness above all things be¬cause God",option:{a:"knew their hearts were right with him",b:"was not interested in their sacrifices",c:"who called them is holy",d:"was searching their sinful   hearts."},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:231,question:"“Father forgive them for they know not what they do” was the prayer said by",option:{a:"Philip",b:"Peter",c:"Paul",d:"Stephen"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2005"},{id:93,question:"In the parable of the sower, the seeds on the good ground represent those who ",option:{a:"Accept and live by the world of God ",b:"feed the poor ",c:"Have and love riches ",d:"Give alms in market places "},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2009"},{id:649,question:"The name Moses means",option:{a:"baptized in water",b:"abandoned in water.",c:"drawn out of water.",d:"thrown into water."},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2011"},{id:180,question:"The son of Solomon who made unwise decisions was ….",option:{a:"Jeroboam      ",b:"Rechoboam",c:"Rehoboam    ",d:"Asa"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2013"},{id:687,question:"‘Death is swallowed up in victory, “oh death, where is your victory”? This statement is found in the book of",option:{a:"Corinthians.",b:"Romans.",c:"Galatians.",d:"Philemon"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2011"},{id:973,question:"Pilate referred Jesus to Herod for trial because",option:{a:"Pilate and Herod were good friends",b:"Jesus did not cooperate with Pilate.",c:"Jesus lived in the jurisdiction of Herod.",d:"Pilate and Herod were enemies."},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2011"},{id:98,question:"For which of these prophets of God did the Bible record explicitly to have abandoned an agribusiness for a call to serve God? ",option:{a:"Elisha ",b:"Ezekiel ",c:"Elijah ",d:"Obadiah."},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:322,question:"When Zechariah saw the angel of the Lord standing on the right side of the altar of incense, he",option:{a:"cried out to him",b:"was troubled and afraid",c:"rejoiced in the Lord",d:"left the Temple immediately."},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2011"},{id:514,question:"“Shall l pursue after this band? Shall l overtake them?” David’s dependence on God for direction is depicted in the statement above when",option:{a:"Absalom had revolted against him",b:"Saul was within his grasp",c:"the Amalekites had raided Ziklag",d:"he was to go against Goliath"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2015"},{id:932,question:"The Philippians showed their solidarity with Paul while in prison by ",option:{a:"using Ephraphroditus to appeal for his release. ",b:"sending gifts to him through Ephaphroditus. ",c:"sending envoys from Corinth to defend him. ",d:"offering regular sacrifices on his behalf"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2013"},{id:574,question:"Apart from the miracles at the wedding feast, another miracle of Jesus at Cana in Galilee was",option:{a:"feeding the four thousand.",b:"healing the noble man’s son.",c:"healing of a man born blind",d:"healing a paralytic man."},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2010"},{id:475,question:"The treasures which Jesus wants us to lay in heaven include",option:{a:"generosity and kindness.",b:"love and mercy.",c:"works of righteousness",d:"gold and silver."},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2009"},{id:374,question:"Peter’s general outlook towards Gentile converts was significantly changed by the conversion of",option:{a:"people of Lydda",b:"the people of Samaria",c:"Simon the magician",d:"Cornelius the centurion."},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2008"},{id:439,question:"According to Paul in his letter to Philemon, forgiveness should not be by compulsion but by",option:{a:"justification",b:"faith",c:"free will",d:"His grace."},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2013"},{id:693,question:"The Galatians, were reminded by Paul that they were Abraham’s offspring and heirs according to",option:{a:"promise.",b:"good works.",c:"law.",d:"grace."},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2011"},{id:446,question:"What in the creation account, gave man an edge over every other creature?",option:{a:"Other creatures were made for man",b:"Man alone was created in the Image of God",c:"Man had the rare privilege to dwell in Eden",d:"Satan acknowledged his privileged position"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2009"},{id:343,question:"‘Pay all of  them their dues, taxes to whom taxes are due, revenue to whom revenue is due, respect to whom respect is due, honour to whom honour is due’. Paul made the statement above to the Church at",option:{a:"Thessalonica",b:"Rome",c:"Corinth",d:"Ephesus."},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2011"},{id:1012,question:" “And I asked them concerning the Jews that survived, who has escaped exile, and concerning Jerusalem...” These were   the words of ",option:{a:"Jeremiah. ",b:"  Nehemiah ",c:" Ezr",d:"Hanani"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2011"},{id:554,question:"When Abner wanted to transfer his allegiance to David, the latter gave him the condition to",option:{a:"openly submit to Joab.",b:"convince all Israel to come over to David.",c:"restore his wife Michal to him.",d:"slay Ishbosheth. Saul’s successor."},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2010"},{id:926,question:"Philip’s flight into Samaria was necesitated by ",option:{a:"the need to convert the Samarians. ",b:"directive from the Holy Spirit. ",c:"persecution of Christians by Saul.",d:"the stoning of Stephen"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2013"},{id:808,question:"The person who discovered the book of law in the sanctuary during the reign of Josiah was ",option:{a:"Zedekiah         ",b:"Huldah.         ",c:"Hilkiah         ",d:"Jeremiah."},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2010"},{id:875,question:"“This is the King of the Jews”This inscription on the cross was meant to show Jesus",option:{a:"charge ",b:"punishment ",c:"victory       ",d:"messiaship"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2012"},{id:3,question:"Jesus’ new commandment according to the Gospel of Jesus of John is ",option:{a:"salvation ",b:"love ",c:"peace ",d:"spirit"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2006"},{id:862,question:"Nehemiah showed concern for this nation by",option:{a:"reviving Yahweh worship",b:"rebuilding the temple",c:"reconstructing Jerusalem walls",d:"leading exiles home"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2012"},{id:197,question:"At the time of creation, the river that flowed out of Eden to water the garden divided into",option:{a:"Pishon, Hauijah, Gihon and Tigris",b:"Tigris, Cush, Assune and Hauijah",c:"Pishon, Tigris, Gihon and Euphrates",d:"Euphrates, Gihon, Assyna and Tigris"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2005"},{id:713,question:"The main message of Hosea is that God desires ___________.",option:{a:"love and sacrifice",b:"sacrifice and thanksgiving",c:"steadfast love and not sacrifice",d:"sacrifice and worship"},section:"",image:"",answer:" c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2019"},{id:412,question:"King Josiah was killed by Pharaoh Neco in a battle at",option:{a:"Syria",b:"Meggiddo",c:"Megiddo",d:"Egypt."},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2013"},{id:1076,question:"One remarkable thing about the feast of Pentecost for Christians was that it ",option:{a:"attracted many foreigners into Israel ",b:"enabled people to speak in tongues ",c:"marked the celebration of grain harvest ",d:"brought home many Jewish nationals"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2015"},{id:172,question:"Render to Caesar the things that they are Caesar’s and to God the things are God’s, the above quotation emphasizes  ",option:{a:"Obedience to divine authority  ",b:"Striking a balance between civil and divine authorities ",c:"Disobedience to civil authority  ",d:"Total rejection of both divine and civil authorities"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2012"},{id:918,question:"“He saved others, he cannot save himself. This was said by the",option:{a:"Scribes and elders.",b:"        Roman authority.",c:"Crowd of people.",d:"        Crucified thieves."},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2013"},{id:664,question:"King Jehoshaphat was commended for adopting his father’s policies which included",option:{a:"removing Maacah, his grandmother from being queen.",b:"waging wars with the king of Israel.",c:"allowing the cult prostitutes to operate.",d:"burning of incense at the high places."},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2011"},{id:201,question:"The name Ichabod means",option:{a:"Yahweh is God",b:"beloved of  Yahweh",c:"I have asked him from the Lord",d:"the glory has departed from Israel."},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2005"},{id:816,question:"In one of the resurrection appearances Jesus asked his disciples, whether they had anything to eat as he ",option:{a:"was hungry after three days in the grave without foo",b:"suspected that the disciples stock may have finished ",c:"wanted to prove to them that he was not a ghost. ",d:"wanted to replenish the food stuff."},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2010"},{id:371,question:"The fate that would befall those who do not receive the gospel of Jesus would be",option:{a:"rejection by men",b:"lack of peace in the family",c:"condemnation by the church",d:"condemnation by God."},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2008"},{id:1043,question:"When Eve was about to be created, God did all the following except.",option:{a:"causing a deep sleep to fall on Adam ",b:"taking a rib from Adam’s side. ",c:"covering where he removed the rib with a bone. ",d:"using the rib to create Eve"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2015"},{id:915,question:"Jesus’ call of the first four disciples to catch men rather than fish implies that they were to ",option:{a:"be trained to become Rabbis. ",b:"convert the Jews into Judaism. ",c:"propagate the teachings of Jesus. ",d:"win proselytes back to Jesus."},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2013"},{id:709,question:"In St. Luke’s record, Jesus specially sent the seventy disciples on mission to _____________.",option:{a:"every town where he was to visit",b:"Gentile cities only",c:"Jewish cities only",d:"plant seeds in the vine yard"},section:"",image:"",answer:" b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2019"},{id:788,question:"To St. James, a doer of the word of God must learn to also__________",option:{a:"persevere in times of tribulation",b:"combine his faith with work",c:"be a listener of the word of God",d:"control his tongue"},section:"",image:"",answer:" d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2019"},{id:328,question:"‘Blessed are you, Simon Bar-Jona ! For flesh and blood has not revealed this to you...’ As exemplified by the statement above, for believers to be able to identify with Jesus, they must",option:{a:"offer their lives",b:"be led by the Spirit",c:"keep all the commandments",d:"vow not to deny Him."},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2011"},{id:396,question:"Paul, unhappy with high incidence of idleness among the Thessalonians, commanded them to",option:{a:"assist those brothers who live in Idleness",b:"exhort the busy-bodies to leave the church",c:"ensure that any one who does not work must not eat",d:"regard the lazy ones as enemies"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2008"},{id:189,question:"Amos reference to ‘cows of Bashan’ was a metaphoric allusion to  ",option:{a:"women of Samaria  ",b:"rich people of Samaria   ",c:"poor people of Samaria  ",d:"illustrious sons of Samaria"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2013"},{id:990,question:"James urged Christians not to be partial but to fulfil the “royal law.” What is the royal law?",option:{a:"You shall not commit adultery",b:"Do good to those who hate you",c:"You should love your neighbour as yourself",d:"Pray for those in authority always"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2011"},{id:712,question:"Divine Love is a ___________love.",option:{a:"stronge",b:"steadfast",c:"strange",d:"shaking"},section:"",image:"",answer:" b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2019"},{id:389,question:"In Romans, Paul taught that where there is no law, there is no",option:{a:"transgression",b:"peace",c:"reward",d:"punishment"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2008"},{id:276,question:"“My spirit shall not abide in man forever, for he is flesh...” When God made the statement above, He concluded that man’s days shall be",option:{a:"one hundred years",b:"one hundred and fifty years",c:"eighty years",d:"one hundred and twenty years."},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2009"},{id:423,question:"“Lord, if you will, you can make me clean.” The statement above was made by the",option:{a:"leper",b:"paralytic",c:"centurion servant",d:"epileptic boy."},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2013"},{id:1055,question:"The main lesson to be learnt from Elijah’s victory at Mount   Carmel is",option:{a:"God empowers his prophets ",b:"the failure of false prophets ",c:"God’s supremacy over false gods ",d:"ability to bring fire from heaven"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2015"}],s={message:e,subject:a,status:200,total:120,data:o};export{o as data,s as default,e as message,t as status,a as subject,i as total};
